Rylʹsʹkyĭ Institute Ukrainian Cylinder Collection, 1908-1930s
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Rylʹsʹkyĭ Institute Ukrainian cylinder collection, 1908-1930s
AFC 1992/005
Archive of Folk Culture, American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
315 items.
7 linear inches (22 folders).
37 sound tape reels: analog, 7 1/2 ips, 2 track; 10 in.
37 sound cassettes (U-Matic audio): digital.
64 photographs: black and white, color; various sizes.
2 videocassettes (VHS): color, sound.
4 diskettes, 3 1/2 in.
Instytut mystet︠s︡tvoznavstva, folʹkloru ta etnohrafiï im. M.T. Rylʹsʹkoho [M.T. Rylʹsʹkyĭ Institute of Art, Folklore Studies and Ethnology], Kiev, Ukraine
This collection of approximately 400 folk songs, folk music, and oral traditions includes sound recorded by Ukrainian ethnologists on wax cylinders in the Ukraine between 1908 and the early 1930s. In a joint project, 212 of approximately 300-400 cylinders in the collection of the Instytut mystet︠s︡tvoznavstva, folʹkloru ta etnohrafiï im. M.T. Rylʹsʹkoho (Rylʹsʹkyĭ Institute) were copied and preserved on audio tape from 1992-1995 at the Library of Congress. Content includes bardic traditions (secular and religious songs), seasonal ritual folk songs (winter carols, spring songs), music of life-cycle rituals (weddings, funerals, laments), as well as ballads and instrumental and ensemble compositions. Of significant note are recordings of blind minstrels (kobzari, lirnyky) probably made during the late 1920s and early 1930s before Stalinist purges. The collection includes musical transcriptions of some of the recordings made by folklorists of the period, including Volodymir Kharkiv, as well as accompanying ethnographic photographs of performers and their instruments dating from the turn of the 20th century and from the 1960s. Additional documentation includes photocopies of slips of paper that were in the cylinder containers, many of which identify the contents of the cylinder. Other photographs document Library of Congress staff member Joseph Hickerson's trip to Ukraine and the Rylʹsʹkyĭ Institute in March 1994. Two videocassettes, produced in 1994, promote the institutional collaboration between the Rylʹsʹkyĭ Institute and the Library.
Scope and Content
The collection materials in the Rylʹsʹkyĭ Institute Ukrainian Cylinder Collection fall into two broad categories: 1) The ethnographic materials including sound recordings, music transcriptions, photographic images, cylinder notes, and 2) Publicity materials (news releases, announcements, presentation flyers, and various clippings that promoted the collection in the U.S. and Ukraine).
The ethnographic materials were collected during the early twentieth century (approximately 1908-1930s) by Ukrainian folklorists and musicologists, and include Ukrainian folk music traditions from various regions of Ukraine including the Kharkiv (Kharkov) region in what was then Soviet Ukraine and the Carpathian region of Eastern Galicia in Interwar Poland (1919-1939). These regions are now part of present day Ukraine.
The collection is primarily comprised of field recordings on wax cylinders held by the Rylʹsʹkyĭ Institute of Art, Folklore Studies and Ethnology (Kiev, Ukraine). There are approximately 400 individual song and instrumental compositions representing several genres and performance styles specific to Ukraine, including bardic traditions (secular and religious songs), seasonal ritual folk songs (winter carols, spring songs), life-cycle rituals (weddings, funerals, etc.), as well as ballads, and instrumental and ensemble compositions. Of significant note are recordings of blind minstrels (e.g., kobzari, lirnyky) probably made during the late 1920s and early 1930s before Stalinist purges, which destroyed the musicians and their distinct performance practices as well as the lives of many of the ethnographers who collected these song traditions.
The collection also includes musical transcriptions of some of the recordings made by folklorists of the period as well as accompanying ethnographic photographs of performers and their instruments dating from the turn of the 20th Century and from 1960. Additional documentation includes photocopies of slips of paper that were in the cylinder containers, many of which identify the contents of the cylinder.
Other photographs document Joseph Hickerson's trip to Ukraine and the Rylʹsʹkyĭ Institute in March 1994. Two videos, produced in 1994, promoting the institutional collaboration between the Rylʹsʹkyĭ Institute and the Library are also included in the collection.
Administrative History
The Maksym T. Rylʹsʹkyĭ Institute of Art, Folklore Studies and Ethnology traces its history back to increased scholarly interest in oral traditions in the early twentieth century. In 1920, the Ethnographic Commission was created and played an integral role in the development of Ukrainian ethnographic and folklore studies. The effort to collect materials related to cultural heritage and traditions in Ukrainian territories was especially productive during the years 1925-1930. The first state-sponsored ethnographic institution in the National Academy of the Ukrainian Soviet Socialist Republic was the Department (Kabinet) of Anthropology and Ethnology named after Fedir (Khvedir) Vovk, founded in 1922. Considerable research in ethnomusicology based on systematic fieldwork in the region using more advanced technologies (e.g., Edison phonograph) was conducted by this department under the direction of Klyment V. Kvitka. A similar effort was underway in Eastern Galicia during the same period, conducted by Ukrainian folklorists and ethnographers. Several ethnographers, including Volodymir Kharkiv (whose musical transcriptions of Ukrainian bards are included in the collection), were very active in collecting oral histories and folk songs during the 1930s, prior to the repressive policies by Joseph Stalin's administration in Soviet Ukraine. Intermittent ethnographic work resumed in 1936 when the Institute of Ukrainian Folklore was established.
The name of the Institute has changed several times. Maksym T. Rylʹsʹkyĭ, who was appointed its director in 1942, headed the Institute of Folk Arts Studies for more than 20 years. Under his directorship, the Institute (since 1944 -- The Institute of Art Studies, Folklore and Ethnography) became a national research center in the studies of culture and art in Ukraine. The Institute was named after M.T. Rylʹsʹkyĭ in 1965. Its current name -- M.T. Rylʹsʹkyĭ Institute of Art, Folklore Studies and Ethnology -- was given in 1994. The Institute currently has several departments: Fine Arts Studies, Ethnic Arts and Culture Studies, Cinema and Theatre Studies, Folklore Studies, Studies of Arts and Folk Culture of Foreign Countries, Ethnology Center, Manuscript Fund, and Academic Library. The Institute also has branches in Khmelnitsky, Mykolaiv, Slovyansk, and Odessa.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
Organizations
Archive of Folk Culture (Library of Congress); Instytut mystet︠s︡tvoznavstva, folʹkloru ta etnohrafiï im. M.T. Rylʹsʹkoho; Library of Congress. Recording Laboratory.
Subjects
Ballads, Ukrainian--Ukraine.; Bandura music.; Bandurists--Ukraine.; Bards and bardism--Ukraine.; Beggars--Songs and music.; Blind musicians--Songs and music.; Blind poets--Songs and music.; Brigands and robbers--Songs and music.; Carols, Ukrainian--Ukraine.; Christmas music--Ukraine.; Costumes--Ukraine--1900-1910.; Cylinder recordings--Ukraine--History.; Dance music--Ukraine.; Dumy, Ukrainian--Ukraine.; Epic poetry, Ukrainian--Ukraine.; Ethnology--Ukraine--20th century.; Flute music--Ukraine.; Flute players--Ukraine.; Folk dance music--Ukraine.; Folk music--Ukraine.; Folk poetry, Ukrainian--Ukraine.; Folk songs, Ukrainian--Ukraine.; Folklore--20th century--Ukraine.; Funeral music--Ukraine.; Gardening--Songs and music.; Hurdy gurdy music--Ukraine.; Hutsuls--Music.; Hymns, Ukrainian--Ukraine.; Instrumental ensembles--Ukraine.; Kobzari--Ukraine.; Laments--Ukraine.; Minstrels--Ukraine.; Musicians--Ukraine--20th century--Photographs.; Musicians--Ukraine--20th century--Social conditions.; Polish people--Ukraine.; Psalms (Music)--Ukraine.; Rites and ceremonies--Ukraine.; Ruthenians--Ukraine--Music.; Salt industry and trade--Ukraine--Songs and music.; Thieves--Songs and music.; Ukrainians--Music.; Vesnianky--Ukraine.; Wedding music--Ukraine.; Weddings--Ukraine--1950-1960.; Work songs--Ukraine.
Places
Carpathian Mountains Region--Social life and customs.; Galicia, Eastern (Ukraine)--Social life and customs.; Ukraine--Social life and customs.
Titles
Ukrainian cylinder collection
Form/Genre
Ballads.; Carols.; Dumy (Music); Hymns.; Interviews.; Photographs.; Songs.; Sound recordings.; Video recordings.; Videocassettes.
Access and Restrictions
Collection is open for research; access to collection materials may be restricted. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Audio duplication for distribution or commercial use must be cleared through the Rylʹsʹkyĭ Institute.
Related Materials
The original cylinders were returned with preservation copies to the Instytut mystetstvoznavstva, Instytut mystet︠s︡tvoznavstva, folʹklorystyky, ta etnolohiï imeni M. Rylʹsʹkoho [M.T. Rylʹsʹkyĭ Institute of Art, Folklore Studies and Ethnology] in Kiev, Ukraine.
Address:
4 Hrushevsky St., 01001, Kiev-1, Ukraine
Phone: (044) 228 3454
E-mail: imfe@ukr.net, etnolog@etnolog.kiev.ua
Collection Concordance by Format
Series I: Manuscripts
22 folders AFC Folders 1-22
Series II: Sound Recordings
37 10-inch reel-to-reel
(preservation tape reels, w/o announcements) M/B/RS RWF 0782-0818
(SR01-SR37)
37 U-Matic DATs
(preservation copy, w/ announcements) M/B/RS RVA 1141-1176
(SR01-SR37)
9 90-minute audiocassettes (copies) AFC SR38-SR46
1 90-minute audiocassette (copy) M/B/RS LWO 28,152
(SR47)
Series III: Graphic Images
38 black-and-white negatives, 35 mm AFC PH01-PH38
2 color prints, 4x6 in. and smaller AFC PH39-PH40
24 black-and-white copy negatives AFC PH41-PH64
Series IV: Moving Images
2 VHS videocassettes AFC MV01-MV02
Series V: Electronic Media
4 diskettes, 3.5 in. AFC CF01-CF04
Container List
- Series I: Manuscripts
  - Draft Finding Aid (2007), 15 pages. (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Song Inventory, 22 pages. (Box-folder 1/2)
    Includes song titles in English and Ukrainian, names of performers when known, song genre, musical instruments, and gender of singer. (This is a printout of CF03 [Box 2, folder 25]).
  - Glossary, 3 pages.
    Definitions of musical terms found in the collection.
  - Ukrainian Wax Cylinders: Notes, 32 pages.
    Summary of the information contained on small pieces of paper that accompanied the wax cylinders. In Ukrainian with English translations.
  - Ukrainian Wax Cylinders: Announcements, 30 pages. (Box-folder 1/3)
    Script for English and Ukrainian announcements made on the Library's copies of the Ukrainian wax cylinders.
  - Transcriptions (1/4), 41 pages. (Box-folder 1/4)
    Made by Volodymir Kharkiv and others in the early 1930s. Transcriptions are mostly of two genres, dumy and psalʹmy; musicians are mostly lirnyky players recorded in eastern Ukraine in the province of Kharkiv.
  - Transcriptions (2/4), 34 pages. (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Transcriptions (3/4), 38 pages. (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Transcriptions (4/4), 30 pages. (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Cylinder Notes, Sample Batch See Folder 2 for transcriptions and translations of these notes., 53 pages. (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Cylinder Notes, First Batch See Folder 2 for transcriptions and translations of these notes., 39 pages. (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Cylinder Notes, Second Batch (1/2), 62 pages. (Box-folder 1/10)
    See Folder 2 for transcriptions and translations of these notes.
  - Cylinder Notes, Second Batch (2/2), 23 pages. (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Cylinder Notes, Third Batch (1/2), 52 pages. (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Cylinder Notes, Third Batch (2/2), 25 pages. (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Cylinder Notes, Addendum, 58 pages. (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Engineer's Notes (1/2), 51 pages. (Box-folder 1/15)
    John Howell's notes from the transfer of the cylinders.
  - Engineer's Notes (2/2), 37 pages. (Box-folder 1/16)
  - Publicity -- LC, 54 pages. (Box-folder 2/17)
    News releases, articles from LC publications, flyers.
  - Publicity -- Non-LC, 38 pages. (Box-folder 2/18)
    News releases, articles. Some in Ukrainian.
  - Scholarly Articles; Kononenko, Natalie. "Duma Pro Chornobylʹ: Old Genres, New Topics." Journal of Folklore Research, Vol. 29, No. 2 (1992): 133-154. (Box-folder 2/19)
  - Noll, William. "The Social Role and Economic Status of Blind Peasant Minstrels in Ukraine." Harvard Ukrainian Studies, 17 (1/2) (1993): 45-71., 23 pages.
    [In Ukrainian] about Benjamin Lukin's expedition.
  - One issue of Rodovid, #6, 1993., 126 pages. (Box-folder 2/20)
    Entire issue on Ukrainian blind bards [in Ukrainian].
  - Selected articles from issues of Rodovid., 70 pages. (Box-folder 2/21)
  - Miscellaneous materials, 3 pages. (Box-folder 2/22)
    Cardboard pages from a shipment of cylinders and/or their documentation.
- Series II: Sound Recordings
  - Duma about a widow Дума про вдову Sung by an unidentified performer Duma, voice, solo, male Song index number: 1.0 Cylinder index number: 35/2 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR01)
  - Duma about a widow, 2nd variation Дума про вдову, 2гий варiянт Sung by an unidentified performer Duma, voice, solo, male Song index number: 2.0 Cylinder index number: 35/3
  - Duma about Turkish slavery Дума про неволю Турецьку Sung by an unidentified performer Duma, voice, solo, male Song index number: 3.0 Cylinder index number: 35/4
  - Duma about Turkish slavery Дума про неволю Турецьку Sung by an unidentified performer Duma, voice, solo, male Song index number: 4.0 Cylinder index number: 35/5
  - "Oh, on Sunday morning" "Ой, у недiлю рано та рано пораненьку" Sung and played by an unidentified performer. Ballad voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 5.0 Cylinder index number: 35/13 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR02)
  - Duma about the three Ozivsʹky brothers Дума про трьох братiв Озiвзьких Sung and played by an unidentified performer. Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 5.1 Cylinder index number: 35/13
  - Duma about the three Ozivsʹky brothers Сольоспiв, Дума про трьох братiв Озiвських Sung by an unidentified performer Duma, voice, solo, male Song index number: 6.0 Cylinder index number: 35/14
  - Duma about a widow and three sons Дума про вдову i трьох синiв Sung by an unidentified performer Duma, voice, solo, male Song index number: 7.0 Cylinder index number: 35/15
  - "Oh, what on Sunday, in the morning" "Ой, що в недiлю, та рано пораненьку" Sung by an unidentified performer Ballad, voice, solo, male Song index number: 7.1 Cylinder index number: 35/15
  - Duma about Konovchenko Дума про Коновченка Sung by an unidentified performer Duma, voice, solo, male Song index number: 8.0 Cylinder index number: 35/16
  - Duma about Marusia Bohuslavka Дума про Марусю Богуславку Sung and played by Larion Honchar Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 9.0 Cylinder index number: 35/23
  - Duma about Marusia Bohuslavka (continuation) Дума про Марусю Богуславку (продовження) Sung and played by Larion Honchar Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 10.0 Cylinder index number: 35/24 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR03)
  - Duma about Marusia Bohuslavka (continuation) Дума про Марусю Богуславку (продовження) Sung and played by Larion Honchar Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 11.0 Cylinder index number: 35/25
  - Duma about a sister and brother Дума про сестру та брата Sung and played by Kobzar Khrystenko Duma, bandura, male Song index number: 12.0 Cylinder index number: 35/43
  - Duma about Oleksi Popovych Дума про Олексiя Поповича Sung and played by Salyvon Veselyj Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 13.0 Cylinder index number: 35/44
  - Duma about Oleksi Popovych Дума про Олексiя Поповича Sung and played by Salyvon Veselyj Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 14.0 Cylinder index number: 35/45
  - Duma about Oleksi Popovych Дума про Олексiя Поповича Sung and played by Salyvon Veselyj Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 15.0 Cylinder index number: 35/46 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR04)
  - Duma about Oleksi Popovych (continuation) Дума про Олексiя Поповича (продовження) Sung and played by Salyvon Veselyj Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 16.0 Cylinder index number: 35/47
  - Duma about the three Ozivsky brothers Дума про троьх братiв Озiвських Sung and played by Nazar Poklad Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 17.0 Cylinder index number: 35/60
  - Duma about the three Ozivsky brothers Дума про троьх братiв Озiвських Sung and played by Nazar Poklad Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 18.0 Cylinder index number: 35/61
  - Duma about the three Ozivsky brothers Дума про троьх братiв Озiвських Sung and played by Nazar Poklad Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 19.0 Cylinder index number: 35/62
  - Duma about the three Ozivsky brothers Дума про троьх братiв Озiвських Sung and played by Nazar Poklad Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 20.0 Cylinder index number: 35/63
  - Duma about the three Ozivsky brothers Дума про троьх братiв Озiвських Sung and played by Nazar Poklad Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 21.0 Cylinder index number: 35/64
  - Duma about the three Ozivsky brothers Дума про троьх братiв Озiвських Sung and played by Nazar Poklad Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 22.0 Cylinder index number: 35/65
  - Duma about the three Ozivsky brothers Дума про троьх братiв Озiвських Sung and played by Nazar Poklad Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 23.0 Cylinder index number: 35/66
  - Duma about the three Ozivsky brothers Дума про троьх братiв Озiвських Sung and played by Nazar Poklad Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 24.0 Cylinder index number: 35/67 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR05)
  - Duma about the three Ozivsky brothers Дума про троьх братiв Озiвських Sung and played by Nazar Poklad Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 25.0 Cylinder index number: 35/68
  - Duma about Marusia Bohuslavka Дума про Марусю Богуславку Sung and played by Larion Honchar Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 26.0 Cylinder index number: 35/72
  - Duma about Marusia Bohuslavka (continuation) Дума про Марусю Богуславку (продовження) Sung and played by Larion Honchar Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 27.0 Cylinder index number: 35/73
  - Duma about Marusia Bohuslavka (ending) Дума про Марусю Богуславку (закінчення) Sung and played by Larion Honchar Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 28.0 Cylinder index number: 35/74
  - Duma about Konovchenko Дума про Коновченка Sung by an unidentified performer Duma, voice, solo, male Song index number: 29.0 Cylinder index number: 35/17
  - "The Adopted Son" "Про Приймака" Sung and played by Bernatsʹky Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 30.0 Cylinder index number: 35/20
  - "The Adopted Son" "Про Приймака" Sung and played by Bernatsʹky Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 31.0 Cylinder index number: 35/21
  - "Oh, on the Pond, the Small Pond" "Ой, на ставi на ставочку" Sung by Bernatsʹky Song, voice, solo, male Song index number: 32.0 Cylinder index number: 35/22 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR06)
  - Duma about a widow Дума про вдову Sung by an unidentified performer Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 33.0 Cylinder index number: 35/28
  - Psalm "Old Mother" Псальма "Стара Матiр" Sung by an unidentified performer Psalm, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 34.0 Cylinder index number: 35/29
  - Duma about a widow Дума про вдову Sung by an unidentified performer Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 35.0 Cylinder index number: 35/30
  - Duma "Hey, on the Black Sea" Дума "Гей, на Чорному Морi" Sung and played by Larion Honchar Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 36.0 Cylinder index number: 35/31
  - Duma about Oleksia Popovych Дума про Олексiя Поповича Sung and played by Larion Honchar Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 36.1 Cylinder index number: 35/31
  - Duma "Hey, on the Black Sea" Дума "Гей, на Чорному Морi" Sung and played by Larion Honchar Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 37.0 Cylinder index number: 35/32
  - Duma about Oleksia Popovych (beginning) Дума про Олексiя Поповича (початок) Sung and played by Larion Honchar Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 38.0 Cylinder index number: 35/35
  - Duma about Oleksia Popovych (conclusion) Дума про Олексiя Поповича (закінчення) Sung and played by Larion Honchar Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 39.0 Cylinder index number: 35/38 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR06 and AFC 1992/005: SR07)
  - "The City Girl" "Мiщаночка" Sung and played by Larion Honchar Song, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 40.0 Cylinder index number: 35/40 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR07)
  - "Orphan Girl" "Сирiтка" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, bandura, male Song index number: 41.0 Cylinder index number: 35/41
  - "Orphan Girl" "Сирiтка" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, bandura, male Song index number: 42.0 Cylinder index number: 35/42
  - "Orphan Girl" "Сирiтка" Sung by an unidentified performer Song, bandura, male Song index number: 43.0 Cylinder index number: 35/50
  - Duma about an orphan girl and a brother Дума про сирiтку та брата Sung by an unidentified performer Duma, bandura, male Song index number: 43.1 Cylinder index number: 35/50
  - Duma about a widow and three sons Дума про вдову i трьох синiв Sung and played by Nestir Kolisnyk Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 44.0 Cylinder index number: 35/54
  - Duma about a sister and a brother Дума про сестру та брата Sung and played by Nestir Kolisnyk Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 45.0 Cylinder index number: 35/58
  - Duma about a sister and a brother (conclusion) Дума про Сестру та Брата (закінчення) Sung and played by Nestir Kolisnyk Duma, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 46.0 Cylinder index number: 35/59 (Tape-id AFC 1992/005: SR08)
  - Duma about a sister and a brother Дума про сестру та брата Sung by Kobzar Makarov Duma, voice, solo, male Song index number: 47.0 Cylinder index number: 35/69
  - Duma about a sister and a brother (conclusion) Дума про сестру та брата (закінчення) Sung by Kobzar Makarov Duma, voice, solo, male Song index number: 48.0 Cylinder index number: 35/70
  - Psalm about Oleksij: Man of God Псальма про Олексiя, Божого чоловiка Sung and played by Nestir Kolisnyk Psalm, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 49.0 Cylinder index number: 35/75
  - Psalm about Oleksij: Man of God Псальма про Олексiя, Божого Чоловiка Sung and played by Nestir Kolisnyk Psalm, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 50.0 Cylinder index number: 35/76
  - Psalm about Oleksij: Man of God (conclusion) Псальма про Олексiя, Божого чоловiка (закінчення) Sung and played by Nestir Kolisnyk Psalm, voice, lira (hurdy-gurdy), male Song index number: 51.0 Cylinder index number: 35/77